Mohammad Mehdi Tilab

Senior JAVA Developer

+98 912 411 22 85 | tilab@tookasoft.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tilab/
GitHub: https://github.com/tookasoft/
LeetCode: https://leetcode.com/tookasoft/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior JAVA developer with experience writing Object Oriented and SOLID clean code for large companies. Expert in J2EE framework such as spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring 5 and etc. I have experience in Linux operation system to deploy web application on there for high availability over Microservice Architecture, caching, clustering and etc. Also, I am expertise in LIFERAY Portal alongside my experience in JAVA, this made me stronger and flexible in enterprise applications.

TECH STACK & Soft Skills

Back End	Java 8 (+5 years) to 17, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring 5, IoC, MVC, AOP, Security, cloud & etc.), REST APIs, Java Web Service SOAP and REST, Lombok, Liferay 3 to 7.3
Front-End & Template engines	HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React Js, ThymeLeaf, FreeMarker
Data Stores	MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB, SQL Server
Web Servers	Apache Tomcat, Apache HTTP Server, Glassfish, Nginx
Operating Systems	Windows, Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS, Oracle Linux, Docker
DevOps	Gitlab CI (continuous delivery, deployment tools, and pipelines), HAProxy, Varnish, Nginx, Apache HTTPd
IDE	IntelliJ Idea, Eclipse
Issue Tracking	JIRA 7 And 8, Trello
Orchestration Platform	Docker Swarm, Kubernetes
Build Tools	Maven, Gradle, Ant
Testing Tools	JUnit 5, Jupiter, Mockito BDD, Cucumber, Gherkin, Rest Assured
Design Pattern	Factory, Singleton, Façade, Strategy, Proxy
Soft Skills	Good Communication Skills, Adaptability, and flexibility in the team , Time management in the critical period, Ability to accept feedback

EXPERIENCE

Senior Java Developer (Fully Remote) | VirtuDev

2021 - Present

- Backend API Development of **Swedish** "Book a Bus".com Startup.
- Stack of Technologies: Java 11, Spring Boot, Security, Rest API, Lombok, Redis, SQL Server

- Using new feature of Modern Java Language such as collection streams, Lambda Expressions, Functional Programming, Method Reference and etc.
- Using **Apache Kafka** as Message Queue for streaming huge requests of mail, SMS, and Push Notification. Also implement Event Sourcing pattern over **Kafka brokers (CQRS)** as event Store.
- Integrate MailJet Email Service API for send mails
- Integrate **Klarna** Payment gateway to payment propose
- Implement Microservice Architecture with Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher and JFrog, and build GitLab ci configuration for CI/CD
- Implement Service Mesh Architecture using Istio
- Using Spring Cloud Services such as Netflix Eureka service registry, Open Feign, Spring Cloud Gateway.
- Make secure API with **Spring Security**, **OAUTH2** and **JWT**
- Using Swagger and Postman for display documentation and test API. and link to each other using HATEOAS
- Make Unit Testing with JUnit 5, Jupiter, Mockito BDD, and Integration Test using SpringBootTest and Rest Assured (Test Driven Design)
- Using Amazon S3 (Simple Storage Service) bucket for store files as data repository.
- Experienced isolating performance errors and mitigating cascading failure to enable resilience in microservice applications that use data streams in which failure is inevitable using **Resilience4j** v.1.7 circuit breakers.

Java Spring Lecturer (Part time) | Anisa Institute

2021 - Present

Anisa education Institute focused on leading Open-source technologies and Java Spring is one of them.

• 120 Hours Spring Class consist of Spring Core, Spring AOP, Security, Spring MVC, Cloud, Microservice and etc.

Senior Java Developer/ Tech Lead | Tookasoft

2010 - 2021

Tookasoft as Knowledge-enterprise Company is known-well in Web Portal industry. Main activity of Tookasoft focus on software development base on java enterprise architecture for mobile and web applications.

- Develop Rightel telecom Self-Care web application that provides various services, from buying packages to paying bills in cluster env with high load traffic. and collecting huge logs via Graylog and cluster mariadb database with galera over 3 nodes. Integrate Some core services with scheduling service base Quartz. Implement 6 bank payment methods with deferent strategy
- Create and develop RIGHTEL portal (3w) By LIFERAY solution such as MNP and SIM card auction, JAVA Base charging application
 include top-up system, develop and integrate API base application, manage OSB system such as install, cluster and define service,
 code review and code analyzer for increase code efficiency. Hardening service by HAPROXY and VARNISH web accelerator
 configuration on LINUX.
- Also, we have implemented a Captive Wi-Fi portal for Telecommunication Company based on LIFERAY 7.1 and integrate with enterprise router such as cisco ASR with Radius protocol.
- In the banking field, we have implemented the Maskan Bank portal with more than 50 subdomains and several other systems, like the registry and follow-up loan system with Spring MVC and hibernate. Also Post Bank with about 6000 service offices all over the country was added to our customers. at first the database was Oracle 11g and upgrade that to 19g and codes and queries qualified again.
- In Investment field, implement form generator, report generator and data dashboard for collecting sales and buy subsidiary companies of Tamin Pharmaceutical and Tamin oil, gas and energy holding using Spring MVC, Hibernate, YUI, ehCache and Apache Lucene.
- In Transportation field, Implement POST company web Portal and Integrate with tracking subsystems via REST API and cluster elastic search.
- Implement mobile bank and internet bank for Sekhavat funds Institute with ReactJS, and REST API and event driven architecture. also Implement backend micro-service with max performance with Spring Boot
- Implement national Innovation Fund portal and Integrate with BIZAGI BPMS for display workflow and stats of used services In cluster env. In project used SQL Server as database.
- Implement Qazvin municipal Portal with 40 subsite and using news workflow based on activity workflow engine.
- Design and optimize micro service architecture.

- Lead a team with high performing developer and engineers as senior java & frontend developers.
- <u>Technologies</u>: JAVA8, JAVA 11, Spring MVC, Spring AOP, Spring-Boot (Spring Cloud & etc.), ReactJS, React Native, Mem-Cache DB like ehCache, Lucene, Elastic, Apache Solr, Activity Workflow engine
- <u>Products:</u> Rightel.ir, my.rightel.ir, bank-maskan.ir, postbank.ir, post.ir, tpico.ir, Inif.ir & etc.

Senior JAVA Developer | Sharif Tech Center (Pishrovan Sharif Company)

2008 - 2010

Sharif tech Center Is subsidiary of Sharif University of Technology, and manage Innovation companies.

- Create and Develop Shasta holding Portal base on EJB 3 and Hibernate 3
- Cerate clustered liferay with load balancer in liferay 5.1
- Upgrade liferay portal 4.2 to 5.1 with new look and feel. Customize Editor for Persian locale and etc
- Create some portlets for example News, News Manager, Mail with Postfix Mail Server configuration, customer satisfaction and etc
- Collaborate to portlet development on Communications Company Portal (MCI.ir)
- Collaborate to portlet development on Social Security Investment Co Portal
- Collaborate to portlet development on Telecommunication Infrastructure Company Portal
- Technologies: JAVA, JAVA EE (Spring MVC, JSF), Hibernate, JPA, MySQL, jQuery.
- **Products:** SSIC.ir, Tamin.ir, MCl.ir

Junior Java Developer | System Group

2006 - 2008

System Group (Hamkaran System) is one of large private software development company in asia. The company provides enterprise software and support to businesses of all sizes located across the country.

- Develop and support exiting web application and fixing bugs for reporting services with SQL Server huge stored procedures.
- Develop customer's portal with liferay Portal 3.3 and upgrade to 4.4 with all side effects and redesign portlet with JSF and jQuery and create resource bundle for Persian locale. Create some Theme using nested apache velocity framework in liferay 4.x.
- Developed dispatcher System for sales managers and experts with EJB3 persistent API.
- Architects, Design and Develop Suggestion flow System Integrated to system group internal site with rule manager and workflow structure with php
- <u>Technologies</u>: JAVA, JAVA EE (Spring3, JSP, Struts-1.3), SQL Server 2008, Hibernate3, JavaScript, Apache Velocity

Frontend Developer | ParsAzarakhsh Co.

2005 - 2006

Pars Azarakhsh, an independent private company, was incorporated in 1988, to provide software solutions, software products and digital data management strategies to governmental and private organization

- Designed National library Web site
- Develop Parslib.com, ParsAzarakhsh official website with php.
- Technologies: PHP 5, MySQL, HTML, CSS.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATIONS

UI UX DuxLab IT Computing	2019
SQLServer Development Sematec IT Computing	2009